A Guide to the Papers of Dr. Edward Watson Hook, Jr., 1947-1998
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- SERIES 1: Professional Organizations & Activities
  - Infectious Diseases Society of America January-December 1976, 48 TLS, 1 TMemo, 4 TD (Box-folder 006-013)
    Re: Miscellaneous business - programming, awards, Journal of Infectious Disease.
  - Infectious Diseases Society of America January-December 1977, 14 TLS, 1 TMemo, 2 TMs (Box-folder 006-014)
    Re: Miscellaneous society business - Journal of Infectious Diseases, Hook's presidential address, "The Evolution of the clinical subspecialist in Infectious Diseases," definition of membership, subspecialists.
  - Infectious Diseases Society of America April 1978-December 1988, 19 TLS, 1 TMs (draft), 4 TMemo, 3 TD (Box-folder 006-015)
  - Interplanetary Society 1969-1976, 9 TLS, 1 TD (Box-folder 006-016)
    Re: Meetings, selection of presentations.
  - Medical Society of Virginia 1970-1987, 13 TLS, 1 TD (Box-folder 006-017)
    Re: programs, unification of Medical Society with AMA.
  - New York Medical & Surgical Society 1968-1989, 6 TLS, 9 TD (Box-folder 006-018)
    Re: Meetings - minutes of meetings in which Hook participated.
  - Southern Society for Clinical Investigation February 1980, 31 TLS, 2 TD, 2 TMs (Box-folder 007-001)
    Re: nomination of officers & members, Journal of Medical Sciences as official society publication, Founder's Award to Hook in 1985.
  - (Virginia) Partners of the Americas 1977-1985, 18 TLS, 5 TD, 4 TMemo (Box-folder 007-002)
    Re: Cooperative medical programs with Brazilian Universities, visit by Hook and Knorr.
  - Royal Society of Medicine August 1984-July 1985, 3 TLS, 1 TD (Box-folder 007-003)
    Re: Hook's participation in conference.
  - Virginia Council on Health & Medical Care; Virginia Academy of General Practice October 1970-September 1974, 9 TLS, 3 TD (Box-folder 007-004)
    Re: Family practice, physician shortage.
  - Virginia Society of Internal Medicine May 1973-March 1981, 13 TLS, 2 TD, 1 TMemo, 1 brochure (Box-folder 007-005)
    Re: ACP/ASIM collaboration; Medicare, primary care.
  - Virginia Council on Internal Medicine October 1975-February 1979, 20 TLS, 3 TMs, 5 TD (Box-folder 007-006)
    Re: Formation of VCIM - manpower study.
  - US - Japan Cooperative Medical Science Program 1982-1985, 1 TMemo, 2 TD, 2 TLS (Box-folder 007-007)
    Re: History of program, meeting documents, reports.
  - US - Japan Cooperative Medical Science Program February-August 1986, 2 TMemo, 1 TD, 8 TLS, 1 pamphlet (Box-folder 007-008)
    Re: Meetings and reports.
  - US - Japan Cooperative Medical Science Program February-September 1987, 4 TMemo, 10 TLS, 2 TD (1 a compilation) (Box-folder 007-009)
  - US - Japan Cooperative Medical Science Program February-July 1988, 1 TMemo, 4 TLS, 3 TD (1 a compilation) (Box-folder 007-010)
    Re: Meetings and reports, Hook-Shimao report on leprosy panel.
  - US - Japan Cooperative Medical Science Program July 1991, 1 TD (compilation) (Box-folder 007-011)
  - US - Japan Cooperative Medical Science Program July 1992, 1 TD (compilation) (Box-folder 007-012)
    Re: Meeting and reports; Hook hepatitis panel review.
  - US - Japan Cooperative Medical Science Program July 1993, 2 TD (1 a compilation) (Box-folder 007-013)
    Re: Meetings and reports; including Hook cholera review report.
  - US - Japan Cooperative Medical Science Program April-August 1994, 8 TLS, 2 TD (1 a compilation) (Box-folder 007-014)
    Re: Meetings and reports; Hook tuberculosis panel report.
  - US - Japan Cooperative Medical Science Program July 1995, 2 TD (1 compilation) (Box-folder 007-015)
  - US - Japan Cooperative Medical Science Program July 1997, 2 TD (1 a compilation) (Box-folder 007-016)
    Re: Meetings and reports; Hook report on malnutrition panel.
  - R. Wood Johnson Minority Medical Faculty Development Program 1991-1992, 1 TLS, 3 TD (compiled) (Box-folder 007-017)
    Re: Hook's reviews of minority scholars' research plans for RSJ Foundation, annual meeting documents.
  - Robert Wood Johnson Clinical Scholars Program 1975-1980, 3 TMemo, 1 TLS, 7 TD (Box-folder 008-001)
    Re: Board meetings, committee on the future of the Clinical Scholars Program.
  - Robert Wood Johnson Clinical Scholars Program 1976-1983, 1 TMs (compilation), 1 journal article copy, 1 TLS (Box-folder 008-002)
    Re: report by Committee on the Future of the Clinical Scholar's program - committee formed by Hook in 1979; he served as exofficio member - recommends that the program continue, article on the program's history.
  - Society for the Right to Die July 1982-October 1983, 12 TLS, 4 TD, 3 TMs, 3 TMemo, 1 ALS (Box-folder 008-003)
    RE: Conference and publication regarding development of guidelines for physicians in terminally ill cases.
  - Society for the Right to Die December 1985-December 1987, 13 TLS, 4 TMemo, 4 TD, 3 TMs (Box-folder 008-004)
    Re: Conference and publication regarding physician's influence on the dying process.
  - Society for the Right to Die January-September 1988, 16 TLS, 3 TMs, 1 TD, 1 printed booklet (Box-folder 008-005)
    Re: Preparation of a publication on physicians and hopelessly ill patients.
  - Society for the Right to Die January-June 1989, 19 TLS, 1 TD, 2 TMemo, 2 TL (Box-folder 008-006)
    Re: Publication of an article in New England Journal of Medicine.
  - International Projects: Cornell November 1962, 1 TMs (Box-folder 008-007)
    Re: "Notes on Trip to Africa and Asia" - described medical care, research, and socio-economic conditions; visits intended to survey possibilities of affiliation between an African hospital and Cornell Medical Center; visits facilities in Nigeria, Lagos, Ibadan, Johannesburg, Nairobi, Kampala, Entebbe, Tororo, Cairo, Karachi, Lahore, Calcutta, Bangkok, Hong Kong, & Tokyo.
  - International Projects: Cornell August-September 1963, 1 TMs (Box-folder 008-008)
    Re: Notes on a Trip to South America" - describes medical care, research, and socioeconomic conditions, visit intended to survey possibilities of affiliation between a South American hospital and Cornell Medical Center, visits to facilities in Bahia, Buenos Aires, Lima, Rio de Janeiro, & Santiago.
  - International Projects: Cornell - Bahia Program 1964-1972, 2 TMs (Box-folder 008-009)
    Re: Summary report 1964-1972, annual report 1964-1965.
  - International Projects: Cornell - Bahia Program 1964-1972, 2 TMs (Box-folder 008-010)
    Re: Annual Report 1963-1966, report of activities 1967-1969.
  - International Projects: Cornell- Bahia Program February 1963-March 1964, 15 TLS, 4 printed/A card, 2 programs, 2 brochures, 1 map (Box-folder 009-001)
    Re: Correspondence and related documents associated with Hook's visits to Brazil prior to establishment of the Cornell-Bahia program.
  - International Projects: Cornell- Bahia Program April 1968-December 1969, 42 TLS, 2 TD, 1 printed invitation, 1 printed brochure, 1 TMs, 1 AMS (Box-folder 009-002)
    Re: Correspondence and related documents associated with Hook's service as head of the program, and subsequent role as consultant.
  - International Projects: Cornell- Bahia Program February 1970-June 1972, 18 TLS, 1 TD, 3 ALS (Box-folder 009-003)
    Re: Correspondence and related documents associated with Hook's role as consultant to the program.
  - International Projects: Cornell- Bahia Program April 1976, 1 TLS, 1 TMs (Box-folder 009-004)
    Re: Part of application for funding to continue project that Hook helped to establish and run.
  - International Projects: NIH - NIAID February 1972-April 1976, 9 TD, 1 TLS (Box-folder 009-005)
    Re: Hook's participation in site visits to projects funded by NIH - NIAID (Title/contents pages only; instructed by NIAID not to retain reports.
  - International Projects: METPAC October 1986-October 1987, 8 TD, 15 TLS, 2 TMemo (Box-folder 009-006)
    Re: Commercial program offering medical seminars to Japanese physicians.
  - Medical Research: Leptospirosis August 1952-February 1955, 12 TMemo, 10 TD, 1 TMs (Box-folder 009-007)
    Re: Medical research done by Hook while in the army in Alabama.
  - Endotoxin-Induced Resistance 195[6-9], 1 TMs (Box-folder 009-008)
    Paper by Hook and Wagner: "Resistance-Promoting Activity of Endotoxins and other Microbial Products".
  - Medical Research: Miscellaneous 1947-1965, 2 TD, 12 TLS, 1 printed program (Box-folder 009-009)
    Re: Streptococcal infections - influenza, pulmonary infection program meeting.
  - Medical Research: Salmonella 1959-1964, 11 TLS, 7 TD, 1 TMs, 1 journal article, 5 TMemo, 1 printed program (Box-folder 009-010)
    Re: Salmonella research - outbreak at New York hospital.
  - Medical Research: Salmonella 1965-1979, 5 TMs, 3 TD, 1 printed program, 3 photograph, 6 TLS, 3 TMemo (Box-folder 009-011)
    Re: Salmonella research, publications, grants, antibiotics use in animal feed.
- SERIES 2: Lectures & Presentations
  - Lectures & Presentations 1972-1985, 3 TD, 16 TMs, 2 printed journal article, 1 AN, 1 printed program, 1 TLS (Box-folder 010-001)
    Re: "Lectures, Talks, Remarks - Book 1, Edward W. Hook" (removed from binder).
  - Lectures & Presentations 1984-1985, 20 TMs, 1 TLS, 2 AN (Box-folder 010-002)
    Re: "Lectures, Talks, Remarks - Book 1, Edward W. Hook," continued (removed from binder); see folder 1 for table of contents.
  - Lectures & Presentations 1985-1986, 9 TMs, 1 T/A MS, 1 TLS, 2 TD (Box-folder 010-003)
  - Lectures & Presentations 1983-1992, 1 AM, 19 TMs, 1 TLS, 1 journal article copy, 1 printed flyer copy, 1 TD (Box-folder 010-004)
    Re: "Lectures, Talks, Remarks - Book II, Edward W. Hook" (removed from binder).
  - Lectures & Presentations 1972-1990, 5 TMs, 9 TLS, 1 printed program (Box-folder 010-005)
    Re: "Health Care and the Medical School: Responsibilities and Responses"; Convocation Address, American College of Physicians, "On My Mind," Alpha Omega Alpha lecture; "Research: A Chairman's Perspective".
  - Lectures & Presentations 1990-1991, 3 TMs, 4 TLS, 3 printed program/brochure (Box-folder 010-006)
    Re: Pacesetters of the American Image, Typhoid Fever and Other Salmonella Infections: Internal Medicine Grand Rounds; Medicare: A Strategy for Quality Assurance.
  - Lectures & Presentations 1993-1996, 2 TMs, 3 TD, 1 journal article reprint, 1 printed program, 1 TLS (Box-folder 010-007)
    Re: Humanities in Medicine: Treatment for a Deficiency Disorder?; Comments at AOA Dinner, Medical College of Pennsylvania.
  - Lectures & Presentations 1996-[n.d.], 2 TLS, 2 TMs, 1 journal article reprint, 10 photographs, 1 AN (Box-folder 010-008)
    Re: Presentation of the 1996 George M. Kober to Robert G. Petersdorf; Medical Education: New Challenges - New Directions; Presidents Address: Pacesetters of the American Image.
- SERIES 3: History of UVa Department of Medicine
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D. [n.d.], 1 TMS (Box-folder 011-001)
    Re: Table of Contents and Chapters I-VII of the Leavell manuscript (removed from black leather binder).
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D. [n.d.], 1 TMS (Box-folder 011-003)
    Re: Professors of Medicine 1900-19 [Chapter VI?] (removed from black leather binder).
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D. [n.d.], 1 TMS (Box-folder 011-004)
    Re: Chapter: Subspecialty Divisions.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D. [n.d.], 1 TMS (Box-folder 011-005)
    Re: Professors of Medicine 1900-19 [Chapter IX] (revised version).
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D. 1980-1983, 4 TMS, 3 TLS, 3 ALS, 3 AN, 1 AD, 4 TD, 1 TN (Box-folder 011-006)
    Re: Revisions, additions to the Leavell manuscript - some by Hook.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D. 1983-1988, 3 TMS, 1 AN, 3 TLS, 1 TDS (Box-folder 011-007)
    Re: Revisions of, additions to Leavell manuscript.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D., Allergy-Pulmonary Division 1976-1978, 7 TLS, 4 TD (Box-folder 011-008)
    Re: Correspondence and notes on the history of the department.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Departments of Ambulatory Medicine and Cardiology Clinical Pharmacology 1976-1978, 1 TLS, 4 TD (Box-folder 011-009)
    Re: Correspondence and notes on histories of departments.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Departments of Epidemiology, Employee Health, and Endocrinology 1976-1978, 10 TLS, 8 TD, 1 AN (Box-folder 011-010)
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Departments of Gastroenterology, Geographic Medicine, and Hematology 1976-1979, 8 TLS, 4 TD, 1 AN (Box-folder 011-011)
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Departments of Infectious Disease, Nephrology, and Oncology 1976-1978, 6 TLS, 4 TD, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 011-012)
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Departments of Rheumatology, Student Health, Geriatrics, and Family Practice 1976-1978, 58 TLS, 4 TD, 2 AD, 1 ANS (Box-folder 011-013)
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Departments of Otolarynology 1979, 2 ALS, 1 TLS, 2 TMS, 1 TD (Box-folder 012-001)
    Re: Manuscript by Fitzhugh on history of otolaryngology at UVa.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Kenneth R. Crispell, M.D. 1955-1965 [n.d.], 12 TD, 1 TMS, 1 ACS (Box-folder 012-002)
    Re: Crispell's career as a faculty member at UVa (press releases), manuscript on Thomas Jefferson and medicine written by Crispell.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Charles L. Crockett, M.D. 1951-1966, 4 TLS, 3 TD (Box-folder 012-00s)
    Re: Correspondence and press releases on Crockett's UVa career.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Staige David Blackford, M.D. March-December 1976, n.d., 12 TD, 1 TMS, 1 ACS (Box-folder 012-004)
    Re: Correspondence and notes on Blackford's UVa career.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Eugene M. Landis, M.D. April-June 1977, 6 TLS, 8 TD (Box-folder 012-005)
    Re: Correspondence and notes on Landis.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Miscellaneous Physicans & Staff 1976-1979, 2 ALS, 5 TLS, 4 TD (Box-folder 012-006)
    Re: Correspondence and notes by and about UVa physicians, including notes from interview with Dr. Thomas Hunter, also information about Hart and Mulholland.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Oscar Swineford, M.D. and Allergy Division 1951-1973, 23 TLS, 16 TD, 1 printed program, 2 ANS, 1 photo, 2 news clippings (Box-folder 012-007)
    Re: Swineford's UVa career, establishment of Swineford Allergy Fund and lectures.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: House staff July 1978, [n.d.], 5 TLS, 1 AN, 1 TD (Box-folder 012-008)
    Re: Correspondence and notes on history of house staff.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Subspeciality Divisions [n.d.], 1 TMs, 29 TD, 1 AD (Box-folder 012-009)
    Re: A rewrite of Leavell's earlier text.
  - History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell, M.D.: Rewrite April 1984, [n.d.], 1 TLS, 1 T&AD, 5 TMs, 7 TD (Box-folder 012-010)
    Re: Maricia Day Finney assists Leavell in re-writting his manuscript, included is re-worked Chapters 1-5 and 5 brief bios on key medical men at UVa.
  - Dr. Byrd S. Leavell, '35, Professor of Internal Medicine July 1942-January 1978, [n.d.], 1 TMs, 29 TD, 1 chart, 4 TL, 14 TLS, 1 form, 1 photo, 10 newspaper clippings, 2 AN, 1 TN, 13 journal clippings, 3 journal articles, 2 brochures, 1 AL (Box-folder 012-011)
    Re: Contents relate to the Leavell's career at UVa, including his curriculum vitae, newpaper & journal clipplins, his participation in conferences, and an essay written on William C. Dabney.
  - Dr. Byrd S. Leavell, Correspondence September 1864-July 1979, 2 AL (Copies), 1 ALS, 1 TL, 1 TLS, 1 newspaper article (copy), 11 ANS, 1 AD (Box-folder 012-012)
    Re: Leavell researches Virginian history, in particular Robert E. Lee.
- SERIES 4: Office Files, alphabetically arranged
  - Affirmative Action November 1974-March 1981, 1 TMemo, 1 TD, 1 TLS, 2 TL (Box-folder 013-001)
    Re: Recruitment of black faculty.
  - AIDS January 1985-December 1987, 25 TLS, 13 TMemo, 7 TD, 1 Diagram, 1 journal/report copy, 1 T/AD (Box-folder 013-002)
    Re: AIDS cases, policies, & procedures at UVa hospital.
  - AIDS February 1988-August 1989, 7 TMemo, 40 TLS, 4 TD, 1 news clipping copy, 2 TMS (Box-folder 013-003)
    Re: AIDS cases, policy, & procedures at UVa hospital.
  - AIDS 1988, 2 TMS (Box-folder 013-004)
    Re: UVa AIDS grant application.
  - AIDS September 1989-August 1990, 7 TMemo, 45 TLS, 6 TD, 3 charts (Box-folder 013-005)
  - Allergy Division September 1980-December 1987, 24 TMemo, 2 TD, 1 TDS, 1 map; 2 printed programs (Box-folder 013-006)
    Re: Personnel, facilities, residency program, conference, etc.
  - Allergy Division January 1988-, 16 TLS, 2 TMemo, 2 TD, 2 printed programs (Box-folder 013-007)
    Re: Personnel, facilities, residencies, conference, etc.
  - Ambulatory Services 1972-December 1987, 19 TLS, 11 TMemo, 10 TD, 1 TMS (Box-folder 013-008)
    Re: Personnel, patient visit statistics and surveys, space allocation, procedures, planning, administration, proposal for outpatient department, ambulatory surgery facility.
  - Ambulatory Services April 1988-May 1989, 9 TMemo, 20 TLS, 6 TD (Box-folder 013-009)
    Re: Personnel, space allocation, patient surveys, productivity, procedures, third year ambulatory care rotation, reorganization, & conferences.
  - Ambulatory Services June 1989-October 1990, 15 TLS, 5 Tmemo, 9 TD, 1 printed brochure (Box-folder 013-010)
    Re: Personnel, productivity, patient surveys, space allocation, ambulatory care education, & information manual.
  - Anesthesiology Department March 1970-April 1990, 4 TMemo, 22 TLS, 1 TD (Box-folder 013-011)
    Re: Personnel, residencies, teaching, patient care, & procedures.
  - AHEC April 1989-October 1990, 32 TLS, 10 TMemo, 1 TD, 1 TMS (Box-folder 014-001)
    Re: Grant proposal for Area Health Education Center.
  - Art, fundraising November 1989-September 1994, 16 TLS, 4 TL, 1 TMs, 1 TD, 1 ALS, 1 copy of check (Box-folder 014-002)
    Re: Documents fundraising attempts to solicit department chairs, includes thank you letters to contributors - Hook is chairman of the committee.
  - Art, fundraising August 1994-November 1994, 1 TL, 10 TLS, 8 TD, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 014-003)
    Re: Soliciting pharmaceutical companies for money to support UVa hopsital's art program - Hook is chairman of the committee.
  - Art, fundraising: Francis Massey Dulaney October 1992-January 1993, 3 TLS, 1 ALS, 1 AN (Box-folder 014-004)
    Re: Soliciting funding for the arts program - Hook is chairman of the committee.
  - Art, Hospital November 1988-May 1995, 1 pamphlet, 2 TMs, 3 TD, 2 TLS, 1 news clipping (copy), 4 journal articles (1st page only), 2 TMemo (Box-folder 014-005)
    Re: The development of a program in the arts at UVA hospital, including prospectus and a document reviewing the minutes of the arts committee from 1988-1995 - Hook is chairman of the committee.
  - Art, Hospital Auxiliary November 1988-1991, 11 TLS (Box-folder 014-006)
    Re: The involvement of the Hospital Auxiliary in rotating art exhibits.
  - Art, Letter & Materials April 1987-July 1989, [n.d.], 5 TD, 22 TLS, 6 TMemo, 2 AN, 8 ALS, 2 Newspaper articles (photocopies), 1 AD, 1 AC, 1 pamphlet (Box-folder 014-007)
    Re: Development of art program and acquisition of works of art, including the prospectus and art forms and also correspondence with various artists.
  - Art, "Medical Art" 1977-1985, 4 Invoice, 19 TD, 3 TL, 1 C, 1 AC, 2 AD, 2 ALS, 5 envelopes with photographs, 3 TLS (Box-folder 014-008)
    Re: Removed from a binder titled "Medical Art"; kept in its original order; contains purchases, invoices, and correspondences with artists.
  - Art, "Medical Art" 1976-1987, 4 invoices, 1 receipt, 1 AD, 10 TD, 1 ANS, 3 TL, 2 ALS, 2 TLS, 2 envelopes w/photos, 1 ACS, 1 ALS w/envelope, 1 pamphlet, 2 C (Box-folder 014-009)
    Re: Removed from a binder titled, "Medical Art"; kept in its original order, contains purchases, invoices, and correspondences with artists.
  - Art, Miscellaneous November 1987-April 1990, 9 TD, 2 TD w/AN, 2 TLS w/AN, 9 TLS, 3 TL, 7 TMemo, 1 ALS (Xeroxed), 4 AD, 1 ALS, 1 TMS (Box-folder 014-010)
    Re: The development and operations of the Health Sciences Arts Committee.
  - Art, Miscellaneous Correspondence 1993-1994, 5 TD, 4 TLS, 2 AD, 1 fax (Box-folder 014-011)
    Re: Correspondence with Ann Johanson, David M. Browne, and Ellen Driscoll.
  - Arts Committee (General) January 1988-November 1990, 1 receipt, 33 TLS, 1 TMs, 5 TD, 3 news clippings, 4 TL, 3 TMemo (Box-folder 014-012)
    Re: Miscellaneous business of the UVa hospital arts committee of which Hook is the chairman; formation of committee and proposed agenda, selection of artists, and other matters concerning placement of portraits and requesting art space.
  - Arts Committee (General, cont.) May 1991-June 1995, 1 TMemo w/AN, 3 TMemo, 18 TLS, 1 xerox of 4 photos, 3 TD, 3 ALS, 1 TL (Box-folder 014-013)
    Re: Miscellaneous business of Arts Committee for UVa hospital which Hook is the chairman, includes discussions of placement of flags, development of patient handbook, art storage and workroom, and continued membership of committee including Hook's farewell letter to committee.
  - Arts Committee, Curator Search November 1991-April 1992, 4 TLS, 5 TMemo, 1 ALS (Box-folder 014-014)
    Re: Selection of an art curator for arts program at UVa hospital.
  - Arts Committee, Membership June 1990-April 1995, 4 TLS, 1 TNS, 1 ALS, 2 TD (Box-folder 014-015)
    Re: Continued membership and new members to the UVa hospitals Arts Committee.
  - Arts Committee 1989 Questionnaire September 1989, 1 TLS, 1 TD, 1 TMs (Box-folder 014-016)
    Re: Results of questionnaire asking for people's opinions of artwork chosen by Arts Committee for UVa hospital.
  - Autopsy March 1974-December 1987, 56 TD, 8 TMemo, 9 TLS (Box-folder 015-001)
    Re: Autopsy guidelines, statistics, permission procedures.
  - Autopsies January 1988-October 1990, 33 TD, 1 TMS, 1 TLS, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 015-002)
    Re: Statistics, report on Autopsy at UVa hospital, and recommendations.
  - Awards August 1980-August 1990, 18 TLS, 7 TMemo, 2 TD, 1 ANS, 1 printed flyer copy (Box-folder 015-003)
    Re: Litz, Culpeper Foundation, Pratt Awards.
  - Behavioral Medicine Division August 1979-November 1990, 4 TMemo, 18 TLS, 6 TD, 1 journal article reprint, 1 program/brochure (Box-folder 015-004)
    Re: Residencies and clerkships, grant proposal, personnel, facilities, evaluation and planning.
  - Biochemistry 1969-1984, 3 TLS, 1 TMemo, 1 ALS (Box-folder 015-005)
    Re: Classes, personnel.
  - Biomedical Engineering 1983-1989, 1 TMemo, 6 TLS, 1 printed brochure (Box-folder 015-006)
    Re: Department name change, hypertonic therapy, conference.
  - Blue Ridge Hospital (clinical) October 1986-August 1989, 13 TMemo, 36 TLS, 6 TD, 4 AN (Box-folder 015-007)
    Re: Internal medicine resident coverage at Blue Ridge, space for geriatrics clinic, shift of adult rehabilitation services to Blue Ridge, problems with care for acute care patients at Blue Ridge, issues concerning space for Internal Medicine at new multi-story hospital.
  - Blue Ridge Hospital (move) January 1979-January 1981, 12 TLS, 1 TD, 1 TMemo, 1 TMs (Box-folder 015-008)
    Re: Proposed plan to build new hospital at Blue Ridge site; opposition by Internal Medicine Faculty.